Guide to the Richard C. Lonsdale Papers 1964-1989 RG 26.8 RG.26.8
New York University Archives
Records of Richard C. Lonsdale
1964-1989
New York University Archives
Lonsdale, Richard C.
RG.26.8
13 Linear Feet 13 linear feet (13 boxes)
Richard C. Lonsdale was a Professor and Chair in the School of Education. The collection consists of his files spanning 1959-1995.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged topically.
The files are grouped into one series:
Missing Title
I, General Files
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains files created during Richard C. Londale's tenure as an administrator in the School of Education.
Historical/Biographical Note
Dr. Richard C. Lonsdale became Professor of Educational Administration and Chairman of the Department of Administration and Supervision in the School of Education of New York University in 1964. The following year his title changed to the Head of the Division of Administration and Supervision, a position he held until 1968 when he resigned from his administrative position and focused his efforts on his professorial duties. Lonsdale later served as member of the NYU Senate and the University Faculty Council.
Access Restrictions
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Provenance
Most of the collection was sent to the University Archives in 1989. The remainder of the collection was sent in 1992.
Minutes (administrative records); Correspondence.; New York University. School of Education; New York University -- Administration
- Series I: General Files
  - School of Education, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225339 6
  - School of Education, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Policy of Administration Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - School of Education (Faculty Meetings), 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - School of Education Faculty Council, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - School of Education (Faculty Meetings), 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - School of Education, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - School of Education (Faculty Meetings), 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - School of Education Task Force Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - School of Education Faculty Council, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - School of Education, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - School of Education Faculty Council, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - School of Education, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - School of Education Budget Advisory Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - School of Education, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - School of Education, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - School of Education, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - SEHNAP Council, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - SEHNAP Council, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - SEHNAP Council, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225340 4
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - SEHNAP Senate, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - SEHNAP Senate, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Facutly Load Report, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - SEHNAP Council, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - SEHNAP Senate, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - SEHNAP Faculty Council, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - SEHNAP Council: Issues Committee, 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - SEHNAP Senate, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - SEHNAP Council, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - SEHNAP Senate, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - SEHNAP Faculty Council, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - SEHNAP Senate, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - SEHNAP Senate: IPD Commission, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - SEHNAP Faculty, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225341 2
  - Griffiths Dinner, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Griffiths Dinner, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Griffiths Dinner, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - University Faculty Council, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - University Faculty Council, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - University Senate, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - University Faculty Council: Committee on Admistration Issues, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - University Senate, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - University Faculty Council, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - University Faculty Council: Committee on Policy, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - University Senate, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - University Senate: Committee on Governance, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - University Senate: McKay Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225342 0
  - Senate Budget Advancement Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - University Faculty Council Personnel Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Case of Iris Polinger, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Case of Mary Smith, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - University Faculty Council, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - University Senate, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - University Faculty Council: NYU Public Information, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - University Faculty Council: Committees, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - University Faculty Council: Strategy Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Univeristy Senate, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - University Senate: Budget Policies Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - University Faculty Council, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - University Senate, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - University Senate: Tenure Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - University Faculty Council, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - University Faculty Council: Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - University Faculty Council: Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Education Administration Faculty, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225343 8
  - Education Administration Faculty, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Education Administration Program, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Education Administration Division, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Education Administration Division Faculty, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - School of Education: "Comparitive Feld Study of Formal Organizations", 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Education Council, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Welfare Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - UCEA, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - SEHNAP Conference: Planning, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - SEHNAP Conferecne: Keynote Speaker, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - SEHNAP Conference: Arrangements, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - SEHNAP Conference: Funding, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - SEHNAP Conference: Panel, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - SEHNAP Conference: Planning Notes, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - SEHNAP Conference: Publicity, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Task Force on Education and Social Policy, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Inactive Materials, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Related Materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Education and Social Policies Committee, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Annual Report, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225344 6
  - Student Information Guide, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Student Information Guide, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Student Information Guide, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Student Information Guide, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Student Information Guide, 1970-1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Dissertation Abstracts, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Dissertation Abstracts, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Dissertation Abstracts, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Student Information Guide, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Student Information Guide, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Student Information Guide, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Annual Report, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Division of Administration and Supervision, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Division of Administration and Supervision, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Division of Administration and Supervision Policy Handbook, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Division of Administration and Supervision Policy Handbook, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Division of Administration and Supervision Faculty Meeting Agendas, 1968-1977 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Division of Administration and Supervision Faculty Meeting Agendas, 1964-1968 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Division of Administration and Supervision, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225345 3
  - Division of Administration and Supervision, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Division of Education Administration, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Division of Education Administration, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Division of Education Administration, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - School of Education Handbook of Graduate Study, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Meetings of Departmental Chairpersons, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Reader Service, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Dissertation Committee Servie, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Robertson Case, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Student Counts by Prgoram, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Hirschman v. NYU, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Tenure Correspondence for Prof. Andrew Marker, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Human Relations Courses, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Human Relations Situations, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Admissions, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Board of Examiners Project, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225346 1
  - Faculty Develpoment Committees, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Department Chairs-meetings, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Department Chairs-meetings, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Department Chairs-meetings, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Department Chairs Evaluations by Faculty, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Orals, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - State Doctor Rev., undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Dvision Heads Meetings, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Division Heads, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - SEHNAP Division of Education Report of Income and Expenses, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - SEHNAP Financial Report, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Education Administration Site Visitors' Reports and Response, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - NCATE Newsletter, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - NCATE, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Fellowships-Faculty, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Organizational and Administrative Studies, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225347 9
  - NCATE, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - NCATE Visitation Team Site Report, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Lonsdale's Report on NCATE, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Memo: Key Points of NCATE Report, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - SEHNAP Institutional Report -NCATE, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Notebook Committee on the Revision of the Program in Education Administration, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - ILSA Program Planning, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Travel Expense Voucher, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Request for Check, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Petty Cash Voucher, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Cash Summary, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Purchase Requisition, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - ILSA Program and Students, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Edelstein, Gerald-ILSA Plan, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Program Deisgn, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Form 99, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - ILSA Organization Theory Group, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - ILSA Program, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - ILSA Program Individual Student, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Notes on Student Conferences, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - ILSA Handbook, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - ILSA Advisees, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - ILSA, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - ILSA General Sessions, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Individual Student Plans, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Comparative Organization Visits, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Call Book, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225348 7
  - E99.3044 Assignment 5, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - E99.3044 Examination, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Journal Masters for Affective Decision Making Study, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Hypotheses, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Permission Letter, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Center Stationery, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Papers Presented for APA Convention, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Loose Papers: Study, Dissertation Schedule, Check Coding, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Instrument #2: Interviw Protocal Content Analysis, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Envelope w/student petition to President Ivan Bennett, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Envelope w/ Clinical Reports, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Envelope w/ Critique and report on Mentally Retarded, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Bernstein, et. Al., 1979 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Berley, et. Al., 1979 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Class Meeting Records, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - E99.3044 Course Book, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Loose Papers-Motor Rating Forms, taskforce reports, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Envelope w/clinical report, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Envelope w/ clinical Board Preparation Class, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Loose Papers - Bernstein Paper, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Survey about dorms?, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Psychological Stress Evaluator Instruments, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Fuichon, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Life History Questionaire, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Resolution, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Envelope w/ Fulchon Correspondence, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Loose Ppaers, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Resolving Social Conflicts - Lewin, Kurt, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Personality and Assessment - Mischel, Walter, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - The Prision Journal, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Issues in Criminology, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Issues in Criminology, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Isuues in Criminologt, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Seminar Report and Thesis- Dorothy Tompkins, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225349 5
  - Administrative Abstract - Dorothy Jaman, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - IRCD Bulletin, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - IRCD Bulletin, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Abstract - Blanche Toma, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - NYU Education Quarterly, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Social Sciences Education Framework for CA Public Schools-Report, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Administrative Abstract - James Robison, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Research Report - Stuart Adams, Dorothy Zi, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Departmental Candidacy Exam - Chief Coordinator Planning Book, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Envelope w/ Dissertation Prospectus, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Envelope w/ Candidacy Exam Review Committee, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - CERC Masterbook, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - MALP Checks - Charting Supervisors, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - MALP Checks - Charting Supervisors, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - MALP Check - PSE manager, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Training Plan for Supervision of Chartering, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Task Record Forms: Blank, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Task Record Forms: Filled Out, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Task List, candidacy exam, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Envelope - Confidential, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Envelope - AID I Clinical Boards, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Envelope - CRC Grading Procedures, undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - E99.3051 Dr. Hawkinshire's Dissertation, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - E99.3044 Class Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Loose Papers, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Faculty Evaluation Procedures, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Human Relations and Social Policy, undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Interdisciplanary, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Recreation and Leiusre, undated (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Files System (EEK!), undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - A.A.H.E., undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Adult Development Commission, undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Alumni Conferences Annual, undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Annual Report, undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Arts, Division of, 1978-1979 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225350 3
  - Association for the Study of Higher Education (ASHE), 1978, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Bi-lingual Special Education Project, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Budget Adminstration, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Budget Development, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Budget Development 1982-1983, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Bulletins and Brochures, 1977-1979 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Capital Projects, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Center for Career Advancement, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Teacher Certification, New York State, 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Challenge Grant, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - CHIP Project, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Extra-universitiy, 1979-1982 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Intra-university, 1980-1982 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Criminal Justice Project, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Dean's Network, 1979-1981 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Department Chair Meetings, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Department Chair Meetings, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Dissertation Proposals Review, 1978-1982 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Division Faculty Meetings, 1977-1982 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Division Course, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Division Heads, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Division Heads Meetings, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Division Head, 1974-1982 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Doctoral Candidacy, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Doctoral Materials, General, 1978-1981 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Education Quarterly, 1979, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Ed.D. Alternate Project, 1974-1979 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Education, Division of - Faculty Meetings, 1977-1981 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Doctoral Orals, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Education Policies Faculty Study Group, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Education, Division of - Budgetary Information, 1977-1981 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Educators in the Community, 1977-1980 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Education Programs Standing Committee, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04225351 1
  - Enrollment Registrar Data, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Environmental Studies Group, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - ERIC, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Development, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - The Community Education Program - A Prospectus, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - SEHNAP Graduate Candidate Record System, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Enrolled Majors by Departments, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Faculty and Faculty Council Minutes and Reports, 1973-1975 (Box 14)